# Curriculum Vitae - Everton Canez F. da Silva

Everton Canez - everton.canez@gmail.com - Version 4.5, Oct 2019

You can download a PDF version here of this resume.

### **About me**

I'm flexible, easy going style with 18y+ hands-on software development experience and practical experience working with web and mobile projects, using CI/CD to automate building processes with Jenkins and TFS.

I'm very capable of working in any team, I'm skilled, specially in javascript using nodeJs and angular, but I'm also experienced in Android and Java. I like front-end and back-end development, I love programming languages and I'm very committed self-learning person.

# **Software Developer**

PROCERGS Aug 2011 – Present Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2011 I started this new position working with Java/PHP/Javascript/HTML/ CSS in several intern projects to solve problems for the management area who wanted to automatize some process and workflow in the company using Oracle Workflow and Java.

Some of this workflows were about implementation of ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library), in disciplines like Configuration Management, Changing Management, Problems Management and so on.

in 2011, after months at this new position, I was invited to be part of the team for mobile/web projects support where I had the responsibility of making research & development for mobile/web technologies. It was the early days of mobile platforms so I started another fase of my career, working with Android Platform.

Through this almost last 9 years I was able to work with several different kind of applications and it led me to work with:

- Android
- UX
- lonic
- Cordova
- Progressive Web Apps
- RESTful APIs
- Restify
- Express
- Java
- OOP
- Micro-services
- JavaScript
- Typescript
- AngularJS
- NodeJS
- Angular 2, 3, 4, 5...

I support development teams who need a consultant and a backup programmer to finish the projects and delivery it on time. I work for teams in transit department, water and sewage department, police and security and many others as allocated team member during the project life cycle and deploy.

I'd like to work with a creative team in projects that make difference for the clients business value.

# **Professional Experience**

### **Technical Operations Engineer**

**PROCERGS** 

February 2005 - August 2010 (5 years 7 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2005 I was invited to join the Technical Operations Team. At this point I was beginning with Java/JSP for software development for the company. At the Technical Operations team I had the opportunity of working in several projects. I started in college and in some point I was responsible for maintaining 6 applications at the same time, all of them communicating with each other via web services (SOAP and after a while RESTful).

At this time it was a common thing the monolithic architecture and so it was for a while. Meanwhile I was having a good progression on my career being promoted each couple of years or so.

### **Technical Specialist**

**PROCERGS** 

March 2000 - January 2005 (4 years 11 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In March 2000, after 3 years in the call center I was invited to become a team member of the Systems Operations Department as Technical Specialist, where I was responsible for developing web systems for the company's intranet. By then I used to program a lot in ASP and had to learn more about data modelling and some Systems Analysis, providing a huge workflow for this department I was working in.

## **Call Center Agent**

**PROCERGS** 

December 1997 - March 2000 (2 years 4 months) Porto Alegre e Região, Brazil

Call center attendant responsible for give support for the clients of several areas like Police Department, Public Security, Water and Sewage Department and Company's Internet Provider clients.

## **System Network Administrator**

Colégio Marista Nossa Senhora do Rosário Porto Alegre e Região, Brasil August 1998 - July 2001 (3 years)

Porto Alegre Area, Brazil Responsible for the administration of school's intranet, network, support and website development

## **Education**

2014 - 2016

Graduate course Computer Software Engineering Universidade de Santa Cruz do Sul

2007 - 2010

University graduate Computer Software Technology/Technician Faculdade de Tecnologia SENAC-RS

## **Main Interests**

- Javascript
- Angular
- Typescript
- NodeJS
- Open Source
- UX
- APIs
- Microservices
- Android
- Java

## **Soft Skills**

- Committed
- Creative
- Passionate
- Proactive
- Productive
- Empathy
- Active listening
- Adaptable
- Business focused
- Enthusiastic
- Collaborative
- Organized

# **Personal Details**

Nome: Everton Canez Ferreira da Silva

Location: Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Social Media: @notreniev, notreniev.github.com

**Skype:** everton.canez@gmail.com **Phone:** Phone: +55 51 991120621

### **Portfolio**

#### Randonneurs Brazil

This is a freelance and the latest project i'm still working on among other things. It consists in a **NodeJS** backend persisting in a **MySQL** database for Randonneurs Brazil, wich is an organization that regulates and approves brevets randonneurs mondiaux, the BRMs, linked to the Audax Club Parisien of ciclism. This backend will attend an **Angular** website and a React Native app.

#### **BMMOB**

An App to help police from Rio Grande do Sul State to attend daily police reports. It was written in **lonic Framework** with **Cordova** to run in **Android** devices. This app comnunicates with a **Java (1.8)** backend on **JBoss Server 7.0** to sinchronize its data with several informations and photos of this reports with an **Oracle Database**.

### **National Address Consulting**

This is a **microservice** writen in **Java** for integration with other Government applications for consuming address in Brazil as a **Java Rest API**. It helps to locate address information in the whole country based on zip code, address, city or state. This **API** was develop using **Java 1.8** running in a cluster of **Jboss Server 6.4** and **Oracle 10** Database.

### **PROCERGS Apps**

This is an internal app store for PROCERGS company to distribute apps for clients who doesn't want to distribute their apps through oficial app stores like Google or Apple. It was written using AngularJS in Front-end, communicating with **Java 1.8 REST API** on back-end, and persisting its data in a **PostgreSQL Database**.

### **Digital School**

Project in partnership with Pontifical Catholic University (PUCRS) and Huawei to informatize school classroom processes in public schools of State of Rio Grande do Sul. Consists in sinchronize classroom information through a mobile app running in a **Android** tablet an then sending all information to a **Jboss server REST API** in the backend with an **Oracle Database**.

### **Turismo RS**

This is an **Android** app for Tourism in the Rio Grande do Sul state. It gives information about the cities, touristic points of interest, places to stay, places to eat, hotels and etc. It communicates with an PHP back-end.

#### Offline ballot box

The popular offline ballot box is an **Android** app that consists of an electronic ballot box app to vote on citizen budget priorities, and it's persisted on a PHP back-end API using a **PostgreSQL**.

Its goal is to bring popular voting to areas without internet access, allowing more citizens to participate on the voting process to prioritise projects on public sector.

Voice List

This is an **Android** app briefly inspired by the GTD (Getting Things Done) concept. It's a personal project wich allow users to create organised lists using their voice and manage those lists to manage tasks, prioritising between active and archived lists and also marking list items as being finished.

**52 Weeks Challenge** 

This is also a personal project writen in **Android** to help users to save money. The goal here is to save a small amount of money every week always doubling this small quantity each week until you get the amount you need to achieve your goals.

## **Technical Skills**

### Languages and Framworks:

- Javascript
- Typescript
- Angular
- NodeJS
- Restify
- Express
- Jest
- Java
- Spring Boot
- Android
- Shell script

#### **Databases:**

- MySQL
- MSSQL
- MongoDB
- SQLite
- Oracle
- PostgreSQL

OS: OSX, Windows

### Tools:

- VSCode
- Eclipse
- Git
- Bash Shell
- Gradle
- Netbeans
- Maven
- Hibernate
- Spring Tools Suite

- Jenkins
- Artifactory

# Language Skills

• Portuguese: Native language

• English: Fluent

## **Personal Interests**

• My family: Father of a little girl and owned by two cats

• Music: Playing guitar, blues, rock, Eric Clapton, Led Zeppelin, AC/DC

• Movies: Star Wars, Indiana Jones, Back to the Future

• TV Shows: The Big Bang Theory, Stranger Things, Brooklin 99, La Casa de Papel

• Programming: Frontend, UX and Backend Development

• Sports: Running, bicycle, swimming

# **Timeline**

1997	1998	2001	2001	2005	2010	2011	2019
Call Center Attendant	HTML Developer	Technical Specialist			Java r Analyst	Mobile Developer	Fullstack Developer

Version 4.5 Last update 2019-10-12 12:10